Guide to the Sinclair Lewis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1888-1950; Series III; 1.67 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - FAMILY AND OTHERS
    - Family
      - [Stepmother], undated (Box 54, Folder 779)
      - Group photos, undated (Box 54, Folder 780)
    - Others
      - Cooke, Grace MacGowan, undated (Box 54, Folder 781)
      - Fisher, Irving, undated (Box 54, Folder 782)
      - Hilsdale, Paul, 1908 April 26 (Box 55, Folder 783)
      - Green, Lucille, undated (Box 55, Folder 784)
      - Penfield, Helen, undated (Box 55, Folder 785)
      - Powers, Katherine, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 786)
      - Powers, Marcella, undated (Box 55, Folder 787-788)
      - Sloane, Arthur J., undated (Box 55, Folder 789)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 55, Folder 790)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF PLAYS
    - "Ah, Wilderness", undated (Box 55, Folder 791)
    - "Angela is Twenty-two", undated (Box 55, Folder 792-793)
    - "Hollywood", undated (Box 55, Folder 794-795)
    - "It Can't Happen Here", [1938?] (Box 55, Folder 796-798)
    - "It Can't Happen Here", [1938?] (Box 56, Folder 799-802)
    - "Shadow and Substance", 1940 (Box 56, Folder 803-804)
  - PLACES
    - Carribean, 1923 (Box 56, Folder 805)
      Includes photographs of Sinclair Lewis
    - Duluth, Minnesota, [1944], undated (Box 56, Folder 806-807)
    - Lewis's homes, undated (Box 56, Folder 808)
    - Sauk Centre, Minnesota, 1902, undated (Box 56, Folder 809-811)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 56, Folder 812-814)
  - OTHER
    - Bust, undated (Box 56, Folder 815)
    - Cat, undated (Box 56, Folder 816)
    - Exhibition, undated (Box 56, Folder 817)
    - Nobel Price, 1930 (Box 56, Folder 818)
    - Photographs used in Mark Schorer's Sinclair Lewis: An American Life, undated (Box 56, Folder 819)
- Personal Papers, 1886-1950; Series IV; 3.34 linear feet (9 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers, housed in boxes 57-64 and 95, is arranged alphabetically by material type.
  The series contains manuscript and printed materials and features diaries and notes dating from 1900 to 1950. The diaries, written in English and in code, date chiefly from 1900 to 1907, and include notes relating to life in high school in Sauk Centre, Minnesota and at Oberlin College and Yale University; there is one late diary dating from 1942 to 1945. Copies of the early diaries include transcriptions of the English-language portions of the text and translations of the coded portions of the text. The twenty-nine folders of notes and notebooks, dating from 1907 to 1950, include research for unidentified writing projects and loose manuscript material.
  - Artwork, 1939, undated (Box 57, Folder 819a)
    Includes original drawings and paintings by Stan MacGovern, Marcella Powers, James Thurber, Francisco Huerta, Glen Ranney, Richard Whorf, and Adolf Dehn
  - Autographs, undated (Box 57, Folder 820)
  - Awards, 1947-1948 (Box 57, Folder 821)
  - Biographical notes on Mildred Walker, 1939 (Box 57, Folder 822)
  - Book plate design, [1912] (Box 57, Folder 823)
  - Calendars, 1941-1949 (Box 57, Folder 824-832)
  - Case history cards, 1908 (Box 57, Folder 833)
  - Certificate for Nobel Prize, 1930
  - "Chronology- Sinclair Lewis", 1932 (Box 58, Folder 834)
  - Clippings, 1906-1931 (Box 58, Folder 835-837)
  - Clippings on Dorothy Thompson, 1932-1940 (Box 58, Folder 838)
  - Contracts, 1912-1947 (Box 58, Folder 839-842)
  - Diaries, 1900-1904 (Box 58, Folder 843-845)
  - Diaries, 1905-1907 (Box 59, Folder 846-847)
  - Diary (typescript copy), 1901-1903 (Box 59, Folder 848-850)
  - Diary (typescript copy), 1904-1907 (Box 60, Folder 851-855)
  - "Minn[esota] diary", 1942-1945 (Box 60, Folder 856-857)
  - Financial papers, 1940, undated (Box 61, Folder 858)
  - Identification cards and passports, 1920-1945 (Box 61, Folder 859-860)
  - "Index of names of characters and places in the works of Sinclair Lewis", undated (Box 61, Folder 861-866)
  - Last will and testament, 1948 October 4 (Box 61, Folder 867)
  - Lists, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 868)
  - Notes and notebooks, 1907-1950 (Box 62, Folder 869-879)
    Includes notes for lectures, notes from A.P. period, and notes on Minnesota, New Haven, CT, and other locations.
  - Notes and notebooks, 1907-1950 (Box 63, Folder 880-893)
  - Notes and notebooks, 1907-1950 (Box 64, Folder 894-897)
  - Printed copy of Balzac's Illusions Perdues with notes, 1909 (Box 64, Folder 898)
  - Printed ephemera, 1886-1906, undated (Box 64, Folder 899-900)
  - Radio program, "American Playhouse", 1943 (Box 64, Folder 901)
  - Readers' club material, 1941-1946 (Box 64, Folder 902)
    Includes correspondence
  - Reproductions of inscriptions from H.G. Wells, undated (Box 64, Folder 903)
  - Schedule, 1937 September 28 (Box 64, Folder 904)
  - School work, 1893-1899 (Box 64, Folder 905)
  - Signatures, 1901-1930 (Box 64, Folder 906)
  - Stage props, undated (Box 95, Folder 906a)
  - Thornton Wilder scripts, undated (Box 64, Folder 907-908)
- Harry E. Maule Material, 1917-1963; Series V; 2.5 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Series V, Harry E. Maule Material, housed in boxes 65-71, is organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Writings, and Other Papers.
  The Harry E. Maule material was acquired by gift from Maule in 1970. Maule was the editor at Random House who oversaw work on Lewis's novels in the 1940s and early 1950s, as well as the collection of Lewis's writings, The Main From Main Street, published in 1963. The arrangement of the correspondence has been preserved in the order given to it by Maule or by earlier processing, with subdivisions for general correspondence, fan mail, and production files. The general correspondence folders contain letters between Lewis and Maule, as well as third party letters relating to Lewis, and the production files contain letters relating to book projects dating from the 1940s and early 1950s.
  The Writings include original drafts by Lewis and drafts and printed versions of work on Lewis. The Other Papers include miscellaneous materials arranged by material type.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - General correspondence, 1939-1952 (Box 65, Folder 909-922)
    - Fan mail, 1948-1951 (Box 66, Folder 923-925)
    - Production files
      - Cass Timberlane, 1946-1947 (Box 66, Folder 926)
      - Gideon Planish, 1947 (Box 66, Folder 927)
      - The God-Seeker, 1948-1949 (Box 66, Folder 928-929)
      - Kingsblood Royal, 1946-1950 (Box 66, Folder 930-935)
      - Lucy Jade, 1948-1950 (Box 66, Folder 936)
      - The Man From Main Street, 1951-1963 (Box 66, Folder 937-940)
      - A Treasury of Brooklyn, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 941)
      - World So Wide, 1950-1951 (Box 67, Folder 942-943)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1920, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 944)
  - WRITINGS
    - Writings by Sinclair Lewis
      - "Storm in the West," screenplay, 1943 August 17 (Box 68, Folder 945)
      - World So Wide, draft, undated (Box 68, Folder 946)
      - Shorter works, 1949, undated (Box 68, Folder 947-948)
      - Shorter works, 1949, undated (Box 69, Folder 949-950)
      - Draft fragments, undated (Box 69, Folder 951)
      - Untitled, [circa 1945] (Box 69, Folder 952)
    - Writings by Others
      - Croy, Homer
        - "Whitman and Sinclair Lewis", undated (Box 69, Folder 953)
      - De Lue, Willard
        - "Legal Residence of Sinclair Lewis in Massachusetts--State Will Get Sizable Sum in Inheritance Taxes", 1951 January 20 (Box 69, Folder 954)
      - Dempster, Margaret Arnold
        - "Satire in the Novels of Sinclair Lewis", 1949 (Box 69, Folder 955)
      - Dickens, Charles
        - "Bleak House," printed version, corrected, undated (Box 69, Folder 956)
      - Feikema, Feike
        - "In Memoriam Address", 1951 January 28 (Box 69, Folder 957)
        - "Sinclair Lewis: An Informal Portrait", 1951 January 26 (Box 69, Folder 958)
      - Guthrie, Ramon
        - "The Labor Novel", 1951 February 1 (Box 69, Folder 959)
      - Katkov, Norman
        - "'Red Lewis Comes Home", undated (Box 69, Folder 960)
      - Kay, [Ida?]
        - Untitled, undated (Box 69, Folder 961)
      - Lewis, Grace Hegger
        - "Sinclair Lewis: A Fontainbleau Memory", 1951 April 15
      - Manson, Alexander
        - "The Last Days of Sinclair Lewis", 1951 March 31 (Box 70, Folder 962)
      - Maule, Harry E.
        - "The Man From Main Street," jacket copy, undated (Box 70, Folder 963)
      - Miller, Perry
        - "The Incorruptible Sinclair Lewis", undated
      - Ortiz, Alicia
        - "Sinclair Lewis", 1947 (Box 70, Folder 964)
          Includes correspondence from the author
      - Rathe, Chuck
        - "Sinclair Lewis Burial", 1951 January 28 (Box 70, Folder 965)
      - Smith, Frazer
        - "Medley", 1948 (Box 70, Folder 966)
      - Thompson, Dorothy
        - "Another Peak Falls", 1951 January 15 (Box 70, Folder 967)
      - Womer, Wayne
        - "Sinclair Lewis Was My Sailor", undated (Box 70, Folder 968)
          Includes correspondence and clippings
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - "Analysis of Requests for July Program", undated
    - Blueprints and material relating to house in Williamstown, MA, 1946
    - Clippings, 1949-1959 (Box 70, Folder 969-970)
    - "Early Notes" in Sinclair Lewis' hand, undated (Box 70, Folder 971-974)
    - House decoration material, 1946 September 24 (Box 70, Folder 975)
    - National Information Bureau Charity inquiries, 1941-1942 (Box 71, Folder 976-982)
    - Photos of Lewis, 1917-1951 (Box 71, Folder 983)
    - Printed ephemera, 1945-1952 (Box 71, Folder 984-985)
    - Publicity, 1926-1951 (Box 71, Folder 986)
    - Royalty statements, 1946-1949 (Box 71, Folder 987)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 71, Folder 988)
- Philip Friedman Material, 1923-1953; Series VI; 0.42 linear feet (1 box)
  Series VI, Philip Friedman Material, is organized into two subseries: Sinclair Lewis Correspondence and General Correspondence. Within subseries letters are arranged alphabetically by recipient or correspondent and then chronologically within files.
  The Philip Friedman material was purchased from Doris Harris Autographs on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund in 1981. Friedman assisted Harry E. Maule in editing The Man From Main Street and then planned to write a biography on Lewis. He abandonded his project when he learned that Mark Schorer was preparing a biography of Lewis.
  The series consists chiefly of third party correspondence about Lewis, dating from spring 1953, solicited by Friedman for the purposes of his biography. Many responses are brief, but there are generous replies from Granville Hicks, Upton Sinclair, and others. There are also several letters from Lewis to others.
  - LEWIS CORRESPONDENCE
    - Caughran, David, 1938 May 1 (Box 72, Folder 989)
    - Fishbein, Morris, 1923-1924 (Box 72, Folder 990)
    - Friedman, Philip, 1948 October 8 (Box 72, Folder 991)
    - Lewis, Claude, 1931-1936 (Box 72, Folder 992)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Acton, Harold Mario Mitchell, 1953 July 19 (Box 72, Folder 993)
    - Allen, Frederick, 1953 April 27 (Box 72, Folder 994)
    - Amrine, Marcella Powers, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 995)
    - Angoff, Charles, 1953 May 19 (Box 72, Folder 996)
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher Langhorne, 1953 April 21 (Box 72, Folder 997)
    - "B" General, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 998)
    - Bacon, Peggy, 1953 June 4 (Box 72, Folder 999)
    - Banning, Margaret Culkin, 1953 April 20 (Box 72, Folder 1000)
    - Bohn, Wm. E. (William Edward), 1953 April 28 (Box 72, Folder 1001)
    - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1953 April 19 (Box 72, Folder 1002)
    - Bryson, Lyman, 1953 April 22 (Box 72, Folder 1003)
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sidenstricker), 1953 April 23 (Box 72, Folder 1004)
    - Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1953 April 6 (Box 72, Folder 1005)
    - Cain, James M. [(James Mallahan)?], 1953 April 25 (Box 72, Folder 1006)
    - Canfield, Cass, 1953 April 29 (Box 72, Folder 1007)
    - Cape, Jonathan, 1953 April 15 (Box 72, Folder 1008)
    - Chapman, Gerard, 1953 September 15 (Box 72, Folder 1009)
    - Conrad, Barnaby, 1953 April 10 (Box 72, Folder 1010)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1953 April 7 (Box 72, Folder 1011)
    - Crawford, Cheryl, 1953 March 30 (Box 72, Folder 1012)
    - Croy, Homer, undated (Box 72, Folder 1013)
    - Derleth, August William, 1953 April 16 (Box 72, Folder 1014)
    - Doubleday and Company, 1953 April 17 (Box 72, Folder 1015)
    - Elder, Donald, 1953 May 13 (Box 72, Folder 1016)
    - "F" General, 1953 May 5 (Box 72, Folder 1017)
    - Farrar, John, 1953 March 30 (Box 72, Folder 1018)
    - Fishbein, Morris, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 1019)
    - Flanagan, Hallie, 1953 April 23 (Box 72, Folder 1020)
    - Freeman, Joseph, 1953 April 29 (Box 72, Folder 1021)
    - Goetz, Ruth, 1953 April 27 (Box 72, Folder 1022)
    - Goldman, Eric Frederick, 1953 April 26 (Box 72, Folder 1023)
    - Hart-Davis, Rupert, 1953 May 29 (Box 72, Folder 1024)
    - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1952 June 24 (Box 72, Folder 1025)
    - Hersholt, Jean, 1953 May 15 (Box 72, Folder 1026)
    - Hicks, Granville, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 1027)
    - Hoffman, Arthur Sullivant, 1953 May 14 (Box 72, Folder 1028)
    - Huebsch, B.W. (BenjaminW.), 1953 (Box 72, Folder 1029)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1953 April 12 (Box 72, Folder 1030)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1953 April 27 (Box 72, Folder 1031)
    - Lewis, Claude B., 1952 December 10 (Box 72, Folder 1032)
    - Lewis, William C. (William Charles), 1953 April 2 (Box 72, Folder 1033)
    - Lindey, Alexander, 1953 April 22 (Box 72, Folder 1034)
    - "M" General, 1953, 1959 (Box 72, Folder 1035)
      Includes copies of letters between Bevil Rudd, Sinclair Lewis, and Grace Lewis
    - Macy, George, 1953 April 29 (Box 72, Folder 1036)
    - Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1953 May 27 (Box 72, Folder 1037)
    - Melchior, Frederic, 1953 April 15 (Box 72, Folder 1038)
    - Menjou, Adolphe, 1953 November 7 (Box 72, Folder 1039)
    - Middleton, George, 1953 May 22 (Box 72, Folder 1040)
    - Morse, Samuel F. B., 1953 September 14 (Box 72, Folder 1041)
    - Mowrer, Edgar, 1953 May 17 (Box 72, Folder 1042)
    - Neumann, Henry, 1953 May 14 (Box 72, Folder 1043)
    - Ostenso, Martha, 1953 April 29 (Box 72, Folder 1044)
    - "P" General, 1953 April 14 (Box 72, Folder 1045)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1953 February 12 (Box 72, Folder 1046)
    - "R" General, 1953 April 28 (Box 72, Folder 1047)
    - Scott, Evelyn, 1953 April 25 (Box 72, Folder 1048)
    - Simon, Richard L. (Richard Leo), 1953 April 22 (Box 72, Folder 1049)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1953 March 23 (Box 72, Folder 1050)
    - Sockman, Ralph W. (Ralph Washington), 1953 June 8 (Box 72, Folder 1051)
    - Stong, Phil, 1953 April 12 (Box 72, Folder 1052)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1953 November 18 (Box 72, Folder 1053)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1953 July (Box 72, Folder 1054)
    - Tippett, Tom, 1953 January 21 (Box 72, Folder 1055)
    - Troughbridge, Vincenzo, 1953 March 13 (Box 72, Folder 1056)
    - Updegraff, Allan, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 1057)
    - Van Doren, Irita, 1953 February 25 (Box 72, Folder 1058)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1962 January 10 (Box 72, Folder 1059)
    - Warren, Dale, n.y. May 12 (Box 72, Folder 1060)
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1953 April 14 (Box 72, Folder 1061)
    - Williams-Ellis, Amabel, 1953 April 28 (Box 72, Folder 1062)
    - Wolman, Leo, 1953 July 13 (Box 72, Folder 1063)
    - Wood, Audrey, 1953 April 13 (Box 72, Folder 1064)
    - Zilboorg, Gregory, 1953 April 27 (Box 72, Folder 1065)
    - Empty Envelopes, 1953 April 10 (Box 72, Folder 1066)
- Morgan Guaranty Trust Company Material, 1917-1946; Series VII; 0.21 linear feet (1 box)
  Series VIII, Morgan Guaranty Trust Company Material, is arranged alphabetically by material type.
  The Morgan Guaranty Trust Material was acquired by gift from the company in 1985. The series consists of financial and legal records relating to property owned by Lewis in North Dakota.
  - Assignment of Mortgage, 1917, 1927 (Box 73, Folder 1067)
  - Building contract, 1935 August 10 (Box 73, Folder 1068)
  - Contract for Deed, 1943 June (Box 73, Folder 1069)
  - Correspondence, 1916-1940 (Box 73, Folder 1070)
  - Creditor's Agreement, 1935 June 17 (Box 73, Folder 1071)
  - Envelopes with notes, 1928, undated (Box 73, Folder 1072)
  - Farm Cropping Agreement, 1930-1943 (Box 73, Folder 1073)
  - Farm Loan Application, 1917 November 30 (Box 73, Folder 1074)
  - Financial papers, 1940, 1943 (Box 73, Folder 1075)
  - First Mortgage Note, 1917 November 30 (Box 73, Folder 1076)
  - Insurance policies, 1935, 1938 (Box 73, Folder 1077)
  - Interest Note, 1917 November 30 (Box 73, Folder 1078)
  - Mortgage, 1917 November 30 (Box 73, Folder 1079)
  - Power of Attorney, 1934 April 2 (Box 73, Folder 1080)
  - Receipts, 1930-1939 (Box 73, Folder 1081)
  - Satisfaction of Mortgage, 1937 March 30 (Box 73, Folder 1082)
  - Sheriff's Deed, 1931-1941 (Box 73, Folder 1083)
  - Tax receipts, 1929-1944 (Box 73, Folder 1084)
  - Tax statements, 1935-1946 (Box 73, Folder 1085)
- Oversize, 1911-1951; 27.38 linear feet (18 boxes) + 7 broadside folders
  - Publicity for Ann Vickers (In Series I), undated (Box 74, Folder 1086)
  - Galley proof for Arrowsmith (In Series I), 1925 (Box 74a, Folder 1087)
  - Page proof for Arrowsmith (In Series I), 1925 (Box 74a, Folder 1088)
  - Galley proof for Bethel Merriday (In Series I), 1939 November (Box 74b, Folder 1089)
  - Galley proof for Cass Timberlane (In Series I), 1945 March (Box 74b, Folder 1090)
  - Page proof for Cass Timberlane (In Series I), 1945 April 10 (Box 74b, Folder 1091)
  - Page proof for Cass Timberlane (In series I), 1945 April 18 (Box 75, Folder 1092)
  - Galley proof for Dodsworth (In series I), undated (Box 75, Folder 1093-1094)
  - Page proof for Dodsworth (In series I), 1929 (Box 75, Folder 1095)
  - Galley proof for "Dodsworth" adaptation (In Series I), [1933?] (Box 76, Folder 1096)
  - Page proof for "Dodsworth" adaptation (In Series I), 1933-1934 (Box 76, Folder 1097)
  - Galley proof for Elmer Gantry (In Series I), [1926-1927?] (Box 76, Folder 1098)
  - Page proof for Elmer Gantry (In Series I), 1927 (Box 76, Folder 1099)
  - Galley proof for Gideon Planish (In Series I), 1943 January 12 (Box 77, Folder 1100)
  - Page proof for Gideon Planish (In Series I), 1943 January 25 (Box 78, Folder 1101)
  - Page proof for The God-Seeker (In series I), 1949 (Box 79, Folder 1102)
  - Galley proof for Kingsblood Royal (In Series I), 1946 October (Box 79, Folder 1103)
  - Page proof for Kingsblood Royal (In Series I), 1946 November 21 (Box 79, Folder 1104)
  - Galley proof for The Man Who Knew Coolidge (In Series I), 1928 January (Box 79, Folder 1105)
  - Page proof for The Man Who Knew Coolidge (In Series I), [1928] (Box 79, Folder 1106)
  - Page proof for Mantrap (In Series I), undated (Box 80, Folder 1107)
  - Galley proofs for The Prodigal Parents (In Series I), 1937 October (Box 81, Folder 1108-1109)
  - Page proofs for The Prodigal Parents (In Series I), 1937 October (Box 81, Folder 1110)
  - Publicity for Work of Art (In Series I), undated (Box 81, Folder 1111)
  - Galley proof for World So Wide (In Series I), 1950 September (Box 82, Folder 1112)
  - Page proof for World So Wide (In Series I), 1950 October 13 (Box 83, Folder 1113)
  - Page proof for World So Wide (In Series I), 1950 (Box 84, Folder 1114)
  - Page proof for World So Wide (In Series I), 1950 (Box 85, Folder 1115)
  - Blueprints for stage designs to "Angela is Twenty-Two", 1938 November 29 (Box 1115a (Broadside))
  - Galley proof for review of "Fools, Liars, and Mr. DeVoto" (In Series I), 1944 April 18 (Box 1116 (Broadside))
  - Galley proof for "Obscenity and Obscurity" (In Series I), 1945 July (Box 86, Folder 1117)
  - Galley proof for "Sinclair Lewis: A Few Reminiscences" by Chauncey Brewster Tinker (In Series I), undated (Box 1118 (Broadside))
  - Photographs of Lewis by Robert H. Davis (In Series III), undated (Box 86, Folder 1119)
  - Photographs of Lewis by Trude Fleishmann (In Series III), undated (Box 86, Folder 1120)
  - Photographs of Lewis by Pinchot (In Series III), undated (Box 86, Folder 1121)
  - Photographs of Lewis by Eric Sihaal (In Series III), undated (Box 86, Folder 1122)
  - Photographs of Lewis by Harold Stein (In Series III), undated (Box 86, Folder 1123)
  - Photographs of Lewis by Whitesell (In Series III), undated (Box 86, Folder 1124)
  - Photograph of Calvin Thomas (In Series III), undated (Box 87, Folder 1125)
  - Photographs of Marcella Powers (In Series III), undated (Box 87, Folder 1126)
  - Photographs of [Duluth, MN?] (In Series III), undated (Box 87, Folder 1127)
  - Drawing of Sinclair Lewis (In Series IV), undated (Box 87, Folder 1127a)
  - Certificate of Nobel Prize (In Series IV), 1930 (Box 87a, Folder 1127b)
  - Clipping of poem by Allan Updegraff (In Series IV), 1911 May 6 (Box 88, Folder 1128)
  - Clippings on Dorothy Thompson (In Series IV), 1938-1941 (Box 88, Folder 1129)
  - Envelope for diary typescript (In Series IV), undated (Box 88, Folder 1130)
  - Notes and notebooks (In Series IV), undated (Box 1131 (Broadside))
  - Printed ephemera (In Series IV), undated (Box 88, Folder 1132)
  - "Sinclair Lewis: A Fontainbleau Memory" by Grace Hegger Lewis (In Series V), 1951 April 15 (Box 88, Folder 1133)
  - "The Last Days of Sinclair Lewis" by Alexander Manson (In Series V), 1951 March 31 (Box 88, Folder 1134)
  - "The Incorruptible Sinclair Lewis" by Perry Miller (In Series V), undated (Box 88, Folder 1135)
  - "Analysis of Requests for July Program" (In Series V), undated (Box 88, Folder 1136)
  - Blueprints relating to house in Williamstown, MA (In Series V), undated (Box 88, Folder 1137-1138c)
  - Clippings (In Series V), undated (Box 88, Folder 1139-1141)
  - Photos of Lewis inscribed to Harry Maule (In Series V), undated (Box 88, Folder 1142)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Corporation envelope with notes (In Series VII), undated (Box 88, Folder 1143)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.84 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Writings (In series I) (Box 89, Folder 1144-1156)
  - Correspondence (In Series II) (Box 89, Folder 1157-1192)
  - Personal Papers (In Series IV) (Box 89, Folder 1193-2006)
  - Harry E. Maule material (In Series V) (Box 90, Folder 2007-2045)
  - Philip Friedman material (In Series VI) (Box 90, Folder 2046)
- Restricted Fragile Oversize, 1.34 linear feet (1 box)
  - Personal Papers (In Series IV) (Box 91, Folder 2047-2050)